

Languages

JavaScript

Ruby

C++

Go

IO2

Libraries and Frameworks

Ruby on Rails

React

Backbone

Node.JS

Redux

Tools Used

PostareSQL

NOSL HTML5 / JSX

CSS3 Git Workflow

Heroku

Netlify

Docker

Field Sales Representative

Brooklyn, NY | 561-502-3832 | JZimmsCodes@outlook.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog Personal Portfolio

Summary

Full-stack Software Engineer with experience working in JavaScript and React libraries for frontend and Ruby on Rails for API and backend applications. After 8+ years as a Food and Wine Industry professional, consistency and holding one's self to an increasinaly higher standard are embedded occupational traits.

A natural innovator, a constant re-inventor and a firm believer in the importance of adaptation to surmount any situation.

Proiects

Beverage Inventory and Order Management Environment (B.I.O.M.E.) GitHub | Demo

A single-page application for organizing and ordering product from the perspective of a beverage manager

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Configured Redux within React to store and manage all stately data
- Created a manifest system for updating many items on the backend with just one call to a RESTful API
- Employed React Bootstrap Modals to keep the application to a single page in order to maintain a lightweight appearance

UOweMe - GitHub | Demo

A playful application used to keep track of money owed to you by others for various deeds

- Collaborated with a fellow programmer to make a practical planning app for both comedic relief and usefulness
- Utilized React Router to allow for smoother navigation around the site
- Leveraged JSON Server to provide a simplified API for CRUD functionality
- Deployed the entire application using Heroku for the backend JSON server and Netlify for the React frontend

DeckSwap - GitHub | Demo

An application geared towards Magic: the Gathering enthusiasts, allowing users to rent pre-constructed decks from each other

- Incorporated raw Ruby code to make backend architecture straightforward, clean and expressive
- Implemented many tools available in the vast toolbelt of React to create a dynamic user experience
- Worked with multiple asynchronous functions to make a series of calls from the frontend to backend
- Utilized external API calls from established websites (with permission via API keys), which enhanced the overall user experience

Experience

Domenico Valentino Selections

NYC, NY 07/2019 - 03/2020

- Composed hundreds of well-written sales pitches to attract an ever-expanding customer base each week
- Improved relationship-based accounts spanning all of Manhattan and Brooklyn, creating a steady flow of business throughout the year

Some Good Wine Web Content Manager / Sales NYC. NY 07/2017 - 08/2019

- Developed a web platform using BevMedia and the Shopify API to create a well-received and highly effective storefront
- Ordered wines for inventory and educated customers during customer tasting events

Education

The Flatiron School

Full-Time Software Engineering Immersive

New York, NY 03/2021 - 06/2021

New York, NY 02/2010 - 11/2013



B.S // Food Science